<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Lit Dawn</title><link href="http://terrel.shumway.us/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://terrel.shumway.us/feeds/terrel-shumway.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://terrel.shumway.us/</id><updated>2014-07-30T22:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>A Mouse in my Pocket</title><link href="http://terrel.shumway.us/a-mouse-in-my-pocket.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-30T22:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Terrel Shumway</name></author><id>tag:terrel.shumway.us,2014-07-30:a-mouse-in-my-pocket.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever someone in our family says &amp;quot;We are going to do ...&amp;quot; and the other person does not agree or want to participate, he asks &amp;quot;Do you have a mouse in your pocket? You must, because you said &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, JoyLynn has responded, &amp;quot;Yes, I do have a mouse in my pocket. He helps me keep track of my marbles, so I don't lose them.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after she put on her pajamas, which don't have pockets, she said &amp;quot;Yes, my mouse is in my invisible pocket with my marbles.&amp;quot;  Then she starts imagining a sales pitch for someone trying to sell invisible pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, she told me about a creature she invented called a quadropus. It is like an octopus, but with four tentacles and four eyes evenly spaced aroud its head. I showed her a picture of Octocat, the GitHub mascot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love her creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="silly"></category></entry><entry><title>Heroku is my Hero</title><link href="http://terrel.shumway.us/heroku-is-my-hero.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-30T22:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Terrel Shumway</name></author><id>tag:terrel.shumway.us,2014-07-30:heroku-is-my-hero.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While working on a project for school, I was looking for a simple way to deploy a Django site.  I discovered Heroku. I had heard about Heroku a while back, but got the impression that it was mostly for Ruby, so I didn't investigate too much. (Ruby is a fine language, but for me it doesn't provide enough marginal benefit over Python to justify the effort to learn it well. Maybe someday, but not now.) This latest endorsement of Heroku was by Jacob Kaplan-Moss, one of the co-founders of the Django project, so I took it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was quite pleasantly surprised.
I am now officially spoiled.
Deploying an app was about as simple as it could possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also highlighted a huge hole in my learning.  Heroku uses PostgresQL. Sqlite need not apply because the heroku filesystem is ephemeral. You can create a sqlite database, but as soon as the dyno goes down, your data is gone too. In all of my Djangoing I had never used anything but sqlite. Oops. Then I read about how developing on sqlite (even testing) is a puerile newbie mistake. I guess I really am a newbie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine. If Heroku can use PostgresQL, so can I.  Then I discover that I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don't want to open that can of worms just yet. I'll use sqlite on my development machine, and PostgresQL on heroku. For now. I am beginning to understand why DBAs get paid the big bucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="web"></category><category term="heroku"></category><category term="postgresql"></category></entry><entry><title>First Post!</title><link href="http://terrel.shumway.us/first-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-30T19:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Terrel Shumway</name></author><id>tag:terrel.shumway.us,2014-07-30:first-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test of the pelican site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>